搜索操作
国安局窃听 2010年2月9日
分类  无关
搜索操作
国安局窃听 2010年2月9日
分类  无关
分析音频
我喜欢你这架飞机  弗兰奇
I like your plane, Frankie.
搜索操作
国安局窃听 2010年2月9日
分类  无关
他自己拼起来的
He put it together himself.
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
好吧  不过你晚上可得把蔬菜吃光啊  弗兰奇小子
Okay, but you better eat your vegetables tonight, Frankie boy.
这孩子  就一小坏蛋
That kid. Such a little hooligan.
像他老子
Just like his old man.
你小子可是在风暴来之前
You were the one who toilet papered
把邻居家用卫生纸围了个实在
the neighbor's house right before a thunderstorm,
让妈逮了个正着
until ma busted you.
逼我上门道歉
Marched me over there to apologize.
一把鼻涕一把泪的
Whining and crying.
花了你整整一星期才清理完
Took you, like, a week to clean it all up.
获取部分监护权确实对你有好处  杰西
Getting partial custody's done you good, Jess.
隔周一周末  每周一天
Every other weekend and a day each week.
弗兰奇不用听我和他妈对着吵了
Frankie doesn't have to hear his ma and me hollering at each other.
不错了
Can't complain.
你戒了
And you're dry.
三周后就拿到两周年纪念章了
Get my two-year chip in...three weeks.
你会来参加吧
You coming to the meeting?
绝不错过
Wouldn't miss it.
要是你有课或者
If you have class or something...
不
Don't.
我全靠你才读得起法学院
You're the reason I can afford law school anyway.
我是为了自己有得吹嘘
I'm just doing it for the bragging rights.
我弟弟是律师
My brother the lawyer.
不如说  你弟弟是检察官
How about... your brother the prosecutor?
知道吗
You know?
这才是我真正想要的
That's what I really wanna do.
杰西・勃兰特
Jesse Brandt?
你们是谁
Who are you?
联调局  先生  你得跟我们走一趟
FBI, sir. You need to come with us.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
我们有你的逮捕令
We have a warrant for your arrest.
没事的  孩子
It's okay, son.
你跟彼得叔叔待在一起
You stay with your Uncle Peter.
罪名是什么
What are the charges?
我问你们呢
I asked you a question.
我们不必回答  先生
We don't need to answer your question, sir.
国家安全例外  看逮捕令吧
National security exception. Read the warrant.
我哥哥是航空公司的机械师
My brother's an airline mechanic.
你们抓错人了
You got the wrong guy!
杰西  不会有事的
Jesse, it's gonna be fine.
我会解决的  知道吗
I'll get this sorted out, okay?
威胁分析
威胁  未知
时限  马上
立刻需要补充信息
威胁分析
系统管理员
目前位置未知
生存可能性
关键执行人新任务指派  搜索
查找关键执行人
乖乖开口吧  奥托
You need to talk to us, Otto.
我们只想知道
All we wanna know is...
德西玛的人为什么总是自杀
Why do these Decima guys keep killing themselves?
因为保险合同
It's for the insurance.
所有人加入组织时都有份保单
Each agent gets a policy when they join the organization.
一旦被抓  便一无所有
Get caught, get nothing.
要是出了意外
Have an accident...
家属会获得赔偿金
Their next of kin gets a payday.
这位赔偿金先生是我们找到芬奇的最后线索了
Mr. Payday there was our last lead on Finch.
我们又回到起点了
We're back to square one.
机器说我们还有别的事情需要考虑
The machine says we have other things to worry about.
格里尔抓了芬奇  他就是我们唯一需要考虑的
Greer has Finch. He's the only thing we have to worry about.
我理解你的感受  约翰
I understand how you feel, John.
但她确定哈罗德暂时没有危险
But she assured me Harold's not in immediate danger.
而我们现在还有更大的威胁
And we have a larger threat at hand.
要详说下吗
You wanna expand on that?
她看不清全局
She can't see the full picture.
机器都看不清全局  那要我们如何帮忙
How can we help when the machine can't even see what's going on?
我们当她的耳目
We'll be her eyes and ears.
抱歉  招待不周
I apologize for the... unpleasant accommodation.
终于得见一面  实在荣幸  芬奇先生
It's truly a pleasure to put a face to the name, Mr. Finch.
我对你已是久仰了
I've been wanting to meet you for a long time now.
你想要什么  格里尔先生
What is it that you want, Mr. Greer?
我想谈一下未来
I want to talk about the future.
最够资格谈这一话题的
And who more qualified for that conversation
莫过于人工智能之父了
than the father of artificial intelligence?
利他目标导致的意外副作用罢了
An unintended side effect of an altruistic goal.
利他主义
Altruism?
有意思
Funny.
我还一直以为是出于  创世的权力
I'd always imagined it was about the power of creation.
我自己感受过
I've felt it myself.
你执意将"撒马利亚人"上线
Your endeavor to bring Samaritan online
是在铸成大错
is a grave error in judgment.
你肯定知道这一刻早晚会到来
You must've known this moment would come.
还是你以为无人可以达到你的成就
Or did you think nobody else could accomplish what you did,
你举世无双
that you were unique?
我得承认  你本来把所有人都玩弄于股掌之中了
I must admit you played everyone very well...
直到这一刻
right up until this moment.
现在  你的上帝已经失踪了
And now your God has disappeared,
自行其事了
operating on its own accord.
孩子有时会让人失望
Children can be so disappointing.
这世界需要有组织  芬奇先生
The world needs structure, Mr. Finch...
而"撒马利亚人"可以提供
and Samaritan will provide that.
小心防备伪神  格里尔先生
I'd beware of false idols, Mr. Greer.
你若真的确定"撒马利亚人"没问题
If you were so confident that Samaritan was functional,
又何必大费周章地找我呢
why did you go to such great lengths to find me?
为了盯住你
To keep an eye on you.
身为人工智能之父  你是全世界唯一
As the father of AI, you're the only man in the world
能毁灭它的人
who can destroy it.
那我们现在要如何呢
Where does that leave us then?
待在这儿
Right here.
直到"撒马利亚人"睁开它的眼睛
Until the moment Samaritan opens its eyes.
然后这世界
And then the world...
将不再需要你
will no longer need you.
翻译：阿好  卫老哥  宅女之后  CiciXT  麦结
翻译：幸田实果子  面条打包子  紫杉  天朝直属
时间轴：阿包  凭陵新月  sagelibra
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   校对&总监： 阿好
你刚是偷了死人的钥匙
Did you just steal a dead man's keys?
她要我做的  能借你的刀一用么  约翰
She asked me to. Can I borrow your knife, John?
德西玛太狡猾  肯定不会用GPS
While Decima's too clever to use GPS...
卫星广播带GPS转频器
The satellite radio has a GPS transponder.
小子们也许能找出点数据
The boys might be able to pull off some data,
查出我们新故的德西玛朋友到过哪里
find out where our recently deceased Decima friend has been.
小子们
The boys?
关上门啊  冻死了
Shut the door. It's freezing.
我认识他们
I know them!
他们帮你从科利尔手里救出了我
They helped you rescue me from Collier.
你是那个政府杀手  还逼我拔牙来着
You're that government hit man that made me pull out my molars.
太野蛮了
That's messed up.
放松  凯西  我退休了
Relax, Casey. I'm retired.
他们在这儿干嘛  根
What are they doing here, Root?
北山  杰森  丹尼尔和我一直在四处收集
Daizo, Jason, Daniel, and I have been on the road collecting certain...
三城区的禁品
contraband in the tri-cities.
听着是既含糊又危险啊
That sounds both vague and dangerous.
我希望能借用下你的安全屋  约翰
I was hoping we could use your safe house, John,
毕竟我们之前救他们可费了不少力气
seeing as we went to all the trouble of saving them in the first place.
我真想多跟你情话绵绵一会儿
And as much as I'd love some girl talk,
不过你得去趟卡尔顿酒店
you need to go to the Carlton Hotel.
我要卫星电话干嘛
And, uh, why do I need a satphone?
相信我啦
Trust me.
这个冬天真是够呛
Quite the winter we're having.
我相信你不是来游说全球气候变化的
I don't supposed you're here to sell me on global climate change.
事先防患于未然
It would be nice if we could prepare for the future
好过事后找补
instead of trying to clean up after the past.
我今天要去见总统的情报顾问
I'm meeting with the president's intelligence advisor today.
用试运行的成果说服他们
Use the beta test results to convince them.
"撒马利亚人"是沉睡的巨人
Samaritan is a sleeping giant.
我们需要用信号来唤醒它
We need those feeds to awaken it.
我在努力了
I'm working on it.
别担心  格里尔先生
Don't worry, Mr. Greer.
他们还是想买你的系统
They still wanna buy your system.
"撒马利亚人"不卖  参议员
Samaritan is not for sale, Senator.
德西玛要保留所有权
Decima will retain ownership.
我们会向你们提供关键信息
We will provide you the critical information.
你要我向一家私人公司
You want me to give a private corporation access
提供政府信号权限
to the government feeds--
提供三亿美国人的隐私权限
to 300 million Americans--
好让你们把这些信息再卖回给我们
just so you can sell the information back to us?
"撒马利亚人"比你之前的系统要优秀得多
Samaritan is far superior to your last endeavor.
它能回答你所有的问题
It'll answer all your questions,
它不会给谜语猜
It won't create riddles.
没有待整理的号码
There'll be no numbers to sort through.
没有不确定的罪责
No uncertainties about culpability.
只有纯粹而不受限制的信息
Just pure unfettered information.
我们凭什么同意
Why would we agree to that?
要是我们不能拥有这个系统
If we don't own the system,
那我们还有什么呢
what exactly do we get?
合理推诿
Plausible deniability.
"撒马利亚人"属于独立第三方
Samaritan is privately owned by a third party,
方便你们下次遇着
one that can shoulder the blame
公民权益危机时能推卸责任
for your next civil liberties scandal.
那我要是不答应呢
And if I say no?
我的条件已经说了  参议员
Those are my terms, Senator.
你得扪心自问
You must ask yourself this.
是想阻止恐怖活动
Do you wanna prevent acts of terror...
还是宁可袖手旁观  坐看国家生灵涂炭
or do you wanna stay in the dark and watch your country burn?
就这些了
That's all of 'em.
很好  开始干活吧  小子们
Good. Get to work, boys.
你拿到了"撒马利亚人"七台服务器
You got your hands on seven Samaritan servers.
在上面有发现吗
You find anything on them?
没有  但稍有差池  他们肯定会发现我们
No, but they'll definitely find us if we don't get this right.
需要多久
How long?
数小时
需要的话让杰森帮你
Ask Jason for help if you need it.
他擅长侵入复杂的系统
He's very good at getting into complex systems.
你等会儿会需要
You'll need this later.
你跟我来
You're coming with me.
格林菲尔德不是唯一
Greenfield's not the only one
能够侵入复杂系统的人
who can get into complex systems.
你告诉我详情  我能帮上忙  根
I can help them if you fill me in, Root.
现在不行  约翰
Not now, John.
我要你做点别的事
I need you for something else.
根  我到卡尔顿了  现在怎么做
Root, I'm at the Carlton. What now?
机器不知道具体要找什么
The machine doesn't know exactly what it's looking for,
所以你得把你看到的告诉我
so you'll need to tell me what you see.
我看到
I spy...
政府车牌
government license plates.
特勤局
Secret Service.
分析图像
政府车辆
威胁分析
车牌识别
进入特勤局内网
扫描登记文档
威胁确认
分类  无关
涉及多名目标
■
联系关键执行人.
机器现在肯定是看清楚了
The machine must be seeing clearly now.
我们有号码了
We're getting numbers.
天啊
Oh, my...
五个啊
Five of them.
第一个烧成灰我也认得
And I know the first one by heart.
主控者
Control.
是她的号码
That's whose number we got?
主控者了解机器的工作原理
Control understands how the machine works.
所以她在掩盖自己的行踪
So she's covering her tracks.
机器看到要出事了
The machine saw something.
既然事关主控者  那肯定不是好事
And if Control is behind it, then it's something bad.
机器就让我们做这事吗
Is this really what the machine asked us to do,
喝着烂咖啡  陪着
drink very bad coffee with...
失业的大学毕业生
unemployed college graduates?
耐心点  约翰
Patience, John.
你进去了吗  肖
Are you in, Shaw?
十五楼  如你要求
15th floor, just like you asked.
打算告诉我要去哪儿吗
You wanna tell me where I'm going?
左边第一扇门
First door, down on your left.
想办法进去
You'll need to let yourself in.
你可能要用消音器
You might wanna use your silencer.
别
Don't.
下次你那各种能看的另一半
Next time your all-seeing other half
再想让我闯入满是特勤局特工的房间时
wants me to break into a room filled with secret service guys
预先提醒一下比较好
a little heads up would be great.
她知道你能搞定
She knows you can handle yourself.
行了  可以监控主控者了
Okay, so we've got eyes and ears on Control.
她跟个男人在一起  高个  灰发
She's with some guy-- tall, gray hair.
很严肃啊
Very serious.
罗斯・加里森参议员  我们的第二个号码
Senator Ross Garrison, our second number.
他们其他朋友到了吗
Have their other friends arrived yet?
这女人还有朋友
That woman's got friends?
你要我帮格里尔
You want me to help Greer,
他从我手中偷走了"撒马利亚人"
the man who stole Samaritan from me?
把你的面子先放一边  行吗
Let's put your ego aside for a moment, shall we?
罗斯  我知道"撒马利亚人"是极好的后备计划
Ross, I know that Samaritan is an excellent plan "B."
我只是不喜欢花钱买回
I just don't like having to pay for something
本来就属于我的东西
that belongs to me in the first place.
我不介意你输掉场战役  只要我们能赢得战争
I accept that you lost the battle so we can win the war.
而且  钱不是问题
Besides, money isn't the issue here.
我看过黑色预算  你手上大把钱
I've seen the black budget. You've got plenty.
我们需要的是政府信号
What we need are the government feeds,
这就需要说服其他人
and that's going to take some convincing.
我可没法左右国会的风向  罗斯
I don't control the way the congressional winds blow, Ross.
那应该是你的地盘
I really think that's your arena.
国会那边我在处理
I'm handling congress.
但我们得说服里维拉
But we need Rivera on board.
总统的亲信
The president's bulldog.
我希望你能用你  独特的视角
I need you to use your... special insight
说服他这一项目的优势
to convince him of the program's merits.
我们从"撒马利亚人"的试运行中
There is intel from Samaritan's beta test
发现了有用的情报
that you'll find useful.
我有什么好处
What do I get in return?
一个开放的系统
An open system,
为私人企业所有
one owned by a private entity
让我们得以合理推诿
that gives us plausible deniability
还能继续保护我们的国家
while we continue to protect our country
免受恐怖袭击
from terrorist attacks.
你做这工作已经数年了
You've been doing the job for years.
没人比你更熟悉游戏规则
There's no one better at this game than you.
这不是游戏  而是国家安全
This is not a game, this is national security.
不如让我看看这情报吧
Why don't you let me see the intel?
听到了吗
Are you two hearing this?
他们要跟德西玛勾搭  实行《一九八四》式威权监控
They're ready to get in bed with Decima and go all 1984 on us.
典故出自奥威尔经典政治讽刺小说
我是说  比现在还狠的  我把他们全突突得了
I mean...more than usual. Let me just shoot 'em now.
我们还不知道他们是不是行凶者  肖
We still don't know if they're the perpetrators yet, Shaw.
开玩笑吧
You're joking.
那是主控者  她差点杀了你  根
It's Control. She almost killed you, Root,
还有我  还有哈罗德  还要列举吗
and me and Harold. Should I continue?
人孰无过
We all make mistakes.
看正门  看到什么
Look at the front door. What do you see?
更多政府车牌
More government plates.
-都是号码  -是的
- These our other numbers? - Yes.
国安局的头  卡尔・霍尔库姆将军
Head of the NSA, General Kyle Holcombe,
还有曼纽・里维拉  总统高级顾问
and Manuel Rivera, senior advisor to the president.
那第五个号码呢
And what about the fifth number?
还是个问号
That one's still a question mark.
好吧  就确认一下
Okay, so... just to confirm,
你是说我还不能杀主控者
you're saying I can't kill Control yet.
坚持住啊  萨姆恩
Stay the course, Sameen.
好吧
Fine.
回头要失控了  别怪我没提醒过了
But just remember I told you so when all this goes pear-shaped.
准备找点乐子了吗
You ready to have some fun?
就怕你不问呢
I thought you'd never ask.
他是谁
Who is he?
不知道
I have no idea.
你有见过初生的小马
Have you ever seen a newborn foal
第一次想站起来的样子吗
trying to stand for the first time?
战栗着腿  努力想保持平衡
Those trembling legs trying to balance,
四条腿一直在抖动  直到它终于能站稳
Shaking until the moment it finds itself on all fours.
见证孩子踏出的第一步
Seeing a child walk for the first time...
实在是美妙
is something extraordinary.
但你眼看着自己的孩子站了起来
But you watched your child stand
却又废了它
and then you hobbled it.
你永远不会明白
You could never understand.
你是毁灭者  而非创造者
You're a destroyer, not a creator.
说下去  芬奇先生
I'm listening, Mr. Finch.
我的机器...
The machine...
发展出了我未预料到的能力
it started developing abilities I never expected,
我没有编程过的能力
things I hadn't yet programmed it to do.
那时世上已没有任何算法
And there wasn't an algorithm in the world
能控制它的急速成长
that could control its exponential growth.
等到我自己写出来时
And by the time I figured one out myself
怕是太迟了
it would've been too late.
-什么太迟了  -这还不是问题吗
- Too late for what? - Isn't that just the question?
我的创造  比我自身聪明太多
Having built something significantly smarter than myself,
我如何能预测出其进化
how could I possibly anticipate its evolution?
不确定性  你的无间地狱
Uncertainty. Your personal abyss.
我造机器是要拯救生命
I built the machine to save lives,
但我如何确保机器不会在某天
but how could I be certain that it wouldn't one day
认为全人类都是无关号码
determine that all of humanity was irrelevant?
拜托  不要激活"撒马利亚人"
Please, you cannot allow Samaritan to go online.
一个开放系统所带来的后果
the consequences of an open system
会是灾难性的
will be devastating.
父亲惧怕儿子的力量
The father became fearful of his son,
希腊神话中的泰坦与宙斯  详见S02E13
于是伤害他
so he wounded him.
同样的故事总是一再发生
A tale told time and again.
我并不把"撒马利亚人"视为孩子
I don't think of Samaritan as a child.
我没那么狂妄
I'm not that presumptuous.
但我要让它尽显才华
But I plan to celebrate its brilliance...
而非限制它
not muzzle it.
你自以为能控制如此强大的力量  太过自负
It's pure hubris to think that you can control something so powerful.
谁说我要控制它了
Whoever said I wanted to control it?
我来是当你朋友  罗斯
I'm only here because we're friends, Ross.
总统说得很清楚
The president has made it very clear
他不会再冒险实施其他监控项目了
he will not risk his hide on another surveillance program.
我也不会
Neither will I.
里维拉先生  我能否
Mr. Rivera, if I may--
你当然能
You certainly may.
你一直负责运行这项目
You've been the one running this program.
也该解释解释了
It's high time you explained yourself.
你知道我花了多长时间
Do you know how many hours I've spent
为"北极光"擦屁股打掩护
running interference for this Northern Lights debacle?
所有的公民权益组织  从纽约到香港
Every civil liberties group from New York to Hong Kong
全在为这倒霉东西发疯
has their panties in a twist over this damn thing.
虽然很不幸  但我们还是得保护国家
As unfortunate as that is, we still need to protect our country.
你要我去请求自由世界的领导者
You want me to ask the leader of the free world
批准又一个国民监控项目吗
to approve another domestic surveillance program,
而此时民众还刚开始获知
when people are still learning
前一个见不得人的秘密
the dirty little secrets of the old one?
没戏
I'm not biting.
里维拉先生  你有孩子对吗
Mr. Rivera, you have kids, am I right?
-什么意思  -他们上国家中学
- Your point? - They go to Country Day School.
到底什么意思
Again, your point?
很棒的学校  一流
It's a terrific school, top notch.
在乔治敦27街和0街交界处
It's in Georgetown near 27th and "0" street.
那我告诉你  一年前
What if I told you that, a year ago,
北极光阻止了一起针对乔治敦的恐怖袭击
Northern Lights prevented a terrorist attack in Georgetown?
我们的一名特工拦截并处死了
An operator of ours intercepted and executed
那名恐怖分子
that would-be terrorist.
她发现他在一辆未登记的厢式客车里
She found him sitting in an unmarked sedan
还有一枚放射性炸弹
with a radiological bomb.
他用从牙科X光机里偷来的铯自己做的
It was made from the cesium that he stole from a dental X-ray machine.
你这是编故事逼我就范
You're making up ghost stories to force my hand.
-要有这种事我会知情  -不  你不知情
- I would've heard about this. - No, you wouldn't have.
我们不会每次救完人就发新闻稿
We don't send out a press release every time we save lives,
我们不能
we can't.
当公众站在房顶高喊
And while the public shouts from the rooftops
公民权益时
about their civil liberties...
保护他们的  正是他们
they do so under the protective bubble
所竭力反对的项目
of the very program in which they're railing against,
这项目保护他们免遭恐怖袭击
the one that saves them from terrorist attacks
时时刻刻
every single day,
包括国际的  国内的
International and domestic.
"时刻警惕"  我听过相关汇报
Vigilance. I was briefed on this group.
我们尚不知他们下个目标是什么
We don't know who they're targeting next,
但该组织从不小打小闹
but this group never does anything small.
未来24小时内他们将发动袭击
They're set to strike in the next 24 hours.
唯一能阻止这次袭击的法子
The only way that we can stop this attack
就是再次授权政府信号
is for us to get the government feeds back up
让"撒马利亚人"能尽职工作
and allow Samaritan to do its job.
当然了  要是你打算
Unless of course you want to...
视而不见
ignore the facts,
就等国丧时再去负责清理残骸吧
and you can handle the cleanup duty once there's a national tragedy.
我会仔细看的
I'll read through this.
你慢慢来
Take your time.
可惜我赶时间
Unfortunately I've just run out.
得横穿市区开个会去
I've got a meeting across town.
我回头再找你  曼纽
I'll check in with you later, Manuel.
主控者刚才全场紧逼
Control just went in for the full-court press
准备统治世界了
on total world domination.
现在能杀她了吧
Can I kill her now?
还不行
Not yet.
不管你们要卖什么  我都没兴趣
Listen, whatever you're selling I'm not interested.
他不是卖东西的
He's not selling anything.
我们就是有几个问题想问你
We just have a few questions for you.
最好别动  会加快失血
Probably shouldn't move. It'll bleed more.
尼尔・雅各布斯  纽约驾照
Niall Jacobs, New York license.
你有什么重要的呢  尼尔
Why are you important, Niall?
联邦走狗
Fed pigs.
总是慢半拍
Always ten steps behind.
看来不是政府的人
Guess he's not government.
验证中  病毒验证
震网病毒变体
里面是什么
What is it?
震网改进病毒
A Stuxnet-based virus.
这位创意天才做了什么
What did this creative genius make?
看起来像是自我复制型的蠕虫病毒
Looks like a self-replicating worm.
用来攻击什么系统
Designed to attack what kind of system?
专用微型交换机
A proprietary micro-switcher.
但具体针对什么  她也不知道
But for what... she doesn't know.
武器精良
Expensive hardware...
隐蔽得力
Hiding in plain sight.
训练有素
Well trained.
你是"时刻警惕"的人
You're Vigilance.
你刚是说"时刻警惕"吗  因为
Did you say "Vigilance?" because...
他们来了
they're here.
一定是来干掉主控者和其他人的
It must be to kill Control and the others.
我不太喜欢落井下石
I'm not a big fan of kicking a guy when he's down,
不过
But...
管用啊
sometimes it does the trick.
说出你们的计划
Now tell us your plan.
我只知道我的部分
I only know my part.
所以我们会赢
That's why we're going to win.
我们聪明过你们和你们的法西斯朋友
We're smarter than you and your fascist friends.
你们来不及阻止了
You're too late to stop it from happening.
阻止什么
Stop what?
革命
The revolution.
彼得・勃兰特
已知化名: 彼得・科利尔
威胁  未知
迫近/当前
需要补充信息
关键日期
2010年3月10日
地点  密歇根东区  联邦检察官办公室
扫描文件
为什么花了这么久
Why is it taking so long?
已经两周了
It has been two weeks.
你哥哥在接受联邦调查  勃兰特先生
Your brother's under federal investigation, Mr. Brandt.
他们没有起诉他
They haven't charged him,
甚至不允许他接受审讯时有律师在场
they haven't even allowed him to speak with an attorney.
你们违反了所有法律程序
You are breaking every rule that ensures due process,
别跟我扯什么"国家安全例外"的废话
and do not give me that national security exception crap.
你我都清楚那条法律是应对紧迫威胁的
You and I both know that law was intended for immediate threats.
杰西很可能就是
Jesse very well may be one.
我哥哥这一生从没违反过一条法律
My brother's never broken a law in his life.
他每周工作六十个小时
He works 60 hours a week,
按时付房租  他是个好父亲
he pays his rent on time, he's a good father.
我跟你说  你们抓错人了
I'm telling you you got the wrong guy.
你是个聪明人
You're a bright guy.
显然你深爱你哥哥
And you obviously love your brother...
非常爱  我尊重
very much. I respect that.
但有时候我们至爱之人
But sometimes the people we love the most
会误入歧途
make the worst decisions.
杰西和一个叫阿齐兹・易卜拉欣的人有联系
Jesse has connections to a man named Aziz Al-ibrahim.
易卜拉欣的表亲
Al-ibrahim's cousin
是伊斯兰恐怖组织的人
was part of an Islamist terrorist group
他们在3月11号试图炸毁美国驻埃及大使馆
that tried to blow up an American embassy in Egypt on March 11th.
这只是张照片
This is just a picture.
那我再补充几张
Then let me add to it.
我们甚至不是穆斯林
We're not even Muslim.
这根本说不通啊
I mean, this doesn't make any sense.
这两年你哥哥的生活发生了一些变化
Two years ago your brother made some changes in his life.
他一直在酗酒  他妻子离开了他
He'd been drinking, his wife left him.
但之后  杰西的人生改变了
But then, Jesse turned his life around.
有时候当我们陷入低谷时
Sometimes when we hit bottom...
会求助于错误的人
we ask the wrong people for help--
那些人会利用我们的软弱
people who use our weaknesses against us,
驱使我们做一些  我们本以为自己永远不能做
get us to do things that we never thought we could,
也不会做的事
or would.
这
This...
这不可能是真的
this can't be true.
监视不会说谎  勃兰特先生
Surveillance doesn't lie, Mr. Brandt.
如果我们要对战"时刻警惕"
If we're going up against Vigilance,
我们需要更多的弹药
we're gonna need more ammo.
莱奈尔抓走咖啡店那位之前  我从他身上顺了些
I took some from our coffee shop friend before Lionel picked him up.
弹药应该足以撑到下一站
We should be okay until our next stop.
好极了  又有活儿了
Terrific. More errands.
我们要对抗两个隐形的敌人  约翰
We're fighting two invisible enemies, John.
德西玛和"时刻警惕"都知道机器的事
Decima and Vigilance know about the machine.
他们很聪明  能绕过她行动
These groups are clever, blinding her to their actions.
那就叫你的智囊团快搞定
Then get that brain trust of yours on it.
我受够了机器的搪塞
I'm getting tired of the machine's runaround
芬奇还在别人手里
when Finch is still out there.
你在哪儿
Where are you?
告诉我进度
Gimme a timetable.
她问我们预计时间
She's asking for an ETA.
我们碰到了一些硬件问题
Yeah, we've run into a couple of kinks with the hardware.
必须更新所有设备
We've had to retrofit everything.
要多少时间  丹尼尔
How much time, Daniel?
起码两小时
At least two hours.
地理定位数据怎么样了
What about the geo-locator data?
北山正在弄
Daizo's still working on it.
你不想告诉我接下来去哪儿  好吧
You don't wanna tell me where we're going, fine.
但我要知道你的粉丝团在干什么
But I wanna know what those groupies of yours are working on.
拖延我们的敌人
Something to slow down our enemies.
拿到我们要的东西了吗
Do you have what we need?
今早拿到的
Got it this morning.
肖
Shaw?
我看你可以去跟旧老板聊聊天了
I think it's time you had a chat with your old boss.
马上去
I'm on it.
我们得聊聊我如何宰了她
We'll chat about how I'm gonna kill her.
君子动口不动手
Use your words.
好吧  她这次是受害者
Okay, so she's the victim this time.
那下次呢
But what about the next?
听着  肖
Listen, Shaw.
既然主控者跟格里尔有联系
If Control's in touch with Greer,
她就能带着我们找到哈罗德
she'll lead us to Harold.
你要是一时手痒没忍住
Your trigger finger gets itchy,
我们落了空  他会死
we'll get nothing and he dies.
阴啊  里瑟
Low blow, Reese.
-肖探员  -夫人
- Agent Shaw. - Ma'am.
好久没用枪指着你了
Long time no gunfire.
你认识这女人吗
You know this woman?
记得在你孩子的学校附近处理了
You remember the operator who took out the terrorist
恐怖份子的特工吗
near your children's school?
你想干什么
What do you want?
我真不敢相信我居然要说
I can't believe what I'm about to say.
我是来救你的
I'm here to rescue you.
根
Root.
有什么新消息吗  杰森
You have an update for me, Jason?
杰森和我梳理了病毒的代码
Jason and I combed through the virus's code.
它的攻击目标是定制的微型交换机
It's targeting custom-built micro-switchers
只有一家公司采购过
sold to one company.
哪一家
Which one?
电力公司
The power company.
去帮肖  快
Help Shaw. Hurry.
你有危险
You're in danger.
你们都是
All of you.
你收到了我们的号码
You received our numbers.
还有加里森的
Garrison's too.
一开始还以为你是行凶者
Thought you were the perp at first since, well...
你可害了不少人  夫人
you've stung a lotta frogs, Ma'am.
你为什么要保护我们
Why are you protecting us?
因为这是  计划
'Cause that's part of the... plan.
为了什么大局之类的着想
For the greater good, or something like that.
说实话  我也不知道
Look, honestly, I really don't know.
我只知道马上要出事了
I just know something bad's gonna happen.
肖  我马上过去
Shaw, I'm heading your way.
里瑟  这是怎么回事
Reese? What the hell was that?
你不是说马上要出事吗
You know that bad thing that was gonna happen?
现在出了
I think it just did.
他怎么样
How's he holding up?
他不肯谈
He won't talk about it.
我真不明白
I just don't understand.
杰西本来挺好的
Jesse had been doing so well.
我知道
I know.
那次逮捕打垮了他  彼得
That arrest did him in, Peter.
他们怎么能随便把人扔进监狱
How do they just put someone in jail like that
什么都不说
and not tell you anything?
要是他出来后我没有争取完整监护权
Maybe if I hadn't taken full custody after they let him out...
他酗酒
He was drinking.
你是在保护你的儿子
You were protecting your son.
杰西自杀不是你的错
It's not your fault Jesse killed himself.
我们都要对自己的行为负责
We're all responsible for our own actions.
我去陪陪弗兰奇
I'm go sit with Frankie.
我不想打扰你们
I didn't mean to interrupt.
我只想来说一句
I just wanted to tell you
请节哀顺变
how terribly sorry I am for your loss.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
杰西和我是朋友
Jesse and I were friends.
真的吗
Really?
那我怎么不认识你
Then why don't I know you?
他是我的担保人
He was my sponsor.
要不是杰西  我早就死了
I'd be dead if it wasn't for Jesse.
他挽救了我
He saved my life in so many ways.
真希望我当时有帮他
I wish I had been there for him.
你为什么没有
Why weren't you?
一个远房亲戚害我全家惹上了麻烦
A distant relative caused problems for my family.
我们几乎不认识他  但是
We barely knew him, but...
现在都无关紧要了
that doesn't matter now.
你哥哥是我所认识的最正派的人
Your brother was the most decent man I've ever known.
这个送你  我的朋友
That's for you, my friend.
-我不能接受  -这样你会记得
- I can't. - So you know...
虽然你哥哥杀了自己
that even though your brother killed himself,
但他拯救过别人
he saved someone else.
一系列的停电事故
A series of power failures...
停电事故
纽约五区
获取替换信号
手机信号塔备用电力
纽约电网预计至少要48小时
The NY DWT has estimated at least 48 hours...
成千上万的人在想方设法回家
Thousands of people trying to make their way home...
服务出错
失去信号
还暖和吗  芬奇先生
Are you warm enough, Mr. Finch?
我没事
I'm fine.
停电时我总会想起我的童年
I always think of my youth when the power goes out.
那时停电是
Blackouts were a...
家常便饭
everyday occurrence.
伦敦大轰炸
The Blitz.
德军的空袭持续了九个月
German air raids lasted nine months.
感觉好像几年
Felt like years.
你当时一定很小
You must've been very young.
母亲和我经常睡在地铁隧道里
My mother and I used to sleep in the tube
跟其他许多家庭一样
along with many other families.
有一晚我们去地铁站迟了
One night we were late getting to the station.
我数月来头一次看到夕阳
And I saw the sunset for the first time in...months.
那是我有生以来见过的最美风景
It was the most beautiful thing I'd ever seen.
但那其实并非夕阳
But it wasn't a sunset at all.
而是天空在燃烧
The sky was on fire.
所以你后来参军了吗
Is that why you joined the military?
估计是  鉴于我对你的了解
A high probability, given what I've learned about you
以及你对国家安全的兴趣
and your interest in national security.
当我成人后
By the time I was an adult...
战争已不再那么直接
wars were no longer quite so straightforward.
你加入了军情六处
You were MI6.
民族国家的时代已经结束了  芬奇先生
The era of the nation-state is over, Mr. Finch.
边界已不复存在
There are no more borders.
你没注意到吗
Or hadn't you noticed?
我觉得你高估了
I think you're overestimating
人工智能的力量
the power of artificial intelligence.
你我都清楚事实并非如此
We both know that that is impossible.
战争中  同盟经常会打乱重组
How often alliances shift in times of war.
那些同盟其实  并不存在
Not that those alliances...ever truly exist.
那只是假象
They're an illusion.
如同天空燃烧时  错觉的夕阳
Like seeing a sunset in a sky of flames.
你想通过"撒马利亚人"得到什么
What is it you expect from Samaritan?
我想生活在公正的世界里
I want to live under a more just rule.
"撒马利亚人"永远不会和秘书上床
Samaritan will never sleep with its secretary,
或是贪污挪用竞选经费
or embezzle money from its campaign fund.
它的决策只基于纯粹的逻辑
Its decisions will be based on pure logic.
这  才是我们该推举的领袖
Now...that's a leader deserving of our vote.
好吧  谁带枪了
Okay, who's strapped?
夫人
Ma'am?
我本以为今天有保镖
I thought my protection detail
就火力足够了
would be all the fire power I needed today.
好吧  那你跟在我后边
Okay. Well, then you're behind me.
还有你里维拉  你在右翼  将军
You too, Rivera. Flank right, General.
我们走
Let's roll.
他们在我们后面
They're behind us!
将军
General!
我们走
Let's move.
我下来了  开动发电机
I'm coming down. Start the generator.
解决她
Take care of her!
抱歉来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
不  我看你来得正是时候
No, as far as I'm concerned you were right on time.
根呢
Where's Root?
灯全灭了算怎么回事
And what the hell happened with the lights?
"时刻警惕"向电网上传了病毒
Vigilance uploaded a virus into the power grid.
主控者呢
Where's Control?
科利尔抓走了她和里维拉
Collier got her and Rivera.
不过他们还活着
But he took 'em alive.
"时刻警惕"还有其它计划
Vigilance has something else planned.
是啊  但是什么呢
Yeah, but what?
小子们搞定服务器了吗
Are the boys finished with the servers yet?
-我们快到了  -几分钟就好
- We're almost there. - Minutes away.
抱歉来挤一下
I just had to ride up here for a bit.
后面全是臭男人味儿
It was starting to smell like dude back there.
欢迎来到新泽西
花园之州
终于来了
There you are.
你朋友说什么了
What'd your friend say?
我得警告他们
I have to warn them.
虽然你不会愿意相信我  赫什
You're not gonna believe me, Hersh.
但我们不是来杀主控者的
But we're not here to kill Control.
我们是来救她的
We're here to save her.
撒谎也要有点水平  肖
You can lie better than that, Shaw.
你们停止接受号码
Just 'cause you stopped listening to the numbers
不代表号码就不跳了
Doesn't mean they've stopped coming.
那为什么"时刻警惕"不直接杀了他们
Why didn't Vigilance just kill them?
好问题
That's a good question.
现在真不是时候
Now's not a good time.
记得我说过芬奇暂时没有危险吗
Remember when I said Finch wasn't in imminent danger?
我可能过于轻率了
I may have been a little hasty.
好消息是
In good news...
我知道第五个号码是谁了
I know who the fifth number belongs to.
它被好几个假名掩盖了  但是
It was tucked away under several aliases, but...
军情六处也瞒不了她
even MI6 can't hide from her.
格里尔先生
Mr. Greer.
格里尔抓了芬奇
And Greer has Finch.
就是说"时刻警惕"快抓到他了
Which means that Vigilance is about to have him
除非我们抢先一步
unless we can get to him first.
你们来不及赶到那里了
You won't make it there in time.
"那里"是哪里  根
Where's "there," Root?
尚不清楚
Still too hard to see.
那我们怎么找他
Then how are we supposed to find him?
机器也不知道
The machine doesn't know.
但赫什知道
But Hersh does.
千万小心  肖
Be careful, Shaw.
芬奇在哪里
Where's Finch?
你觉得我知道
You think I know?
我朋友从不出错
My friend is never wrong,
这个  听着都烦人
which is... as annoying as that sounds.
德西玛
Decima.
你知道哪儿能找到他们
You know where to find them?
我凭什么要相信你
Why would I trust you?
我可没朝你开枪  你可是要杀我
I haven't shot you yet and you did try to kill me.
他确实杀了我
He did kill me.
奉命行事罢了
Those were my orders.
再说你也报复了  肖
Besides, you got me back, Shaw.
差得远呢  我只给你下了药
Oh, not even close. I drugged you.
你可是还有心跳呢
I left you with your heart still beating.
好像跑题了
I think we're getting off topic.
说得没错
You're right.
我们必须合作  救出芬奇
We need to work together to save Finch.
救出我们的朋友
We save our friend,
我们就帮你救主控者
then we help you rescue Control.
里瑟
Reese.
必须这样
It's the right move.
该你了  肖
Your turn, Shaw.
休想  乔治
Not on your life, George.
这简直是万无一失嘛
There's no way this could go wrong.
你来晚了
You're late.
你试试在断电时横穿市区
You try getting across town in a blackout.
这是谁
Who's that?
全世界最重要的人  参议员
That is the most important man in the world, Senator,
新纪元之父
the father of the new age.
我手下传来消息
My team just got word
"时刻警惕"绑架了我的同僚
that Vigilance kidnapped my colleagues.
我们得尽快出城
We need to get out of the city.
恐怕我们没有时间了
I'm afraid we won't have enough time.
加里森参议员
Senator Garrison.
知道吗
You know...
你的人真该加密一下短信
your men should really encrypt their text messages.
或者干脆别发短信
Or avoid them altogether.
绑架参议员够你判无期的
Kidnapping a senator will get you life.
格里尔先生
Mr. Greer.
很高兴见到你
Pleasure to make your acquaintance.
我通常不太喜欢惊喜
I'm not usually a fan of surprises,
不过这次
but this...
这次我倒是乐于接受
this is one I'll happily except.
哈罗德  对吧
Harold, is it?
我们上次的谈话被仓促打断了
You know, our last conversation was so rudely interrupted
我还有一堆问题要问你
and I still have so many questions for you.
你和我们一起走
You're coming with us.
兰登呢
So where is Langdon?
他去华盛顿特区工作了
He took a job in D.C.,
不过我很了解你哥哥的案子
but I'm familiar with your brother's case.
你们认为和他同伙的那个人
The man you thought he was working with
其实只是匿名戒酒会的朋友
turned out to be just a friend from AA.
我哥哥不是恐怖分子
My brother wasn't a terrorist.
我听说了你哥哥的事
I heard what happened with your brother,
请节哀顺变
and I am terribly sorry for your loss.
别跟我扯这些陈词滥调了  行吗
Don't give me your platitudes, all right?
是你们逼得他自杀了
You people are the reason he killed himself.
-我们有证据  -你们有个屁
- We had evidence... - You had nothing!
你们肆意关押他
You locked him up under some loophole
直到毁了他
until it destroyed him!
他失去了工作  失去了家庭
He lost his job, he lost his family.
影射产生的谣言  伤害程度如同定罪
Innuendo turned out to be just as damaging as a conviction.
他永远都洗不清
He could never be cleared...
因为政府从没有提出控告
because the government never pressed charges.
无辜之人不会自杀  勃兰特先生
Innocent people don't kill themselves, Mr. Brandt.
不会  失去希望的人会
No, people without hope do.
你们夺去了他的希望
And you robbed him of that.
你们拿着错误的信息  加以屈解
You took the wrong information and you twisted it.
你们应该关押罪犯
You're supposed to lock up the criminals,
而非制造罪犯
not create them.
你们夺去了我哥哥的生命  那你们算什么人
And you took my brother's life, so what does that make you?
短信
未知
我知道你有问题
我有答案
短信
未知
你想知道你哥哥真正的遭遇吗
我的车在外边
My car's out front.
你还想开车吗
You think you're driving?
反正你别想开
You're certainly not driving.
-我来开  -我心领了
- I'll drive. - I'll pass.
好吧  这么办
Okay, here's the deal.
我来开车  里瑟坐在后面
I'm gonna drive, Reese sits in the back,
你坐副驾  同意吗
while you ride shotgun, agreed?
行了  服务器好了
We're done. The servers are ready.
时间正好
Perfect timing.
你们只能到这里了
Because this is as far as you boys go.
你们所需的一切都在里面
Everything you need is inside.
那辆车会送你们每个人去该去的地方
That car'll take each of you where you need to be.
等等
你在说什么
我们已经经历了那么多  不会现在丢下你
Yeah, we've come this far. We're not leaving you now.
她已经计算过了
She's done the math.
一起去的话  你们全都会死  我也一样
If we go together, you all die and... I do too.
我独自前往  胜率会好点
If I go alone, the odds improve.
好一点点
Slightly.
那你到底要去哪儿
And just where are you going exactly?
小子们
Boys...
见见"撒马利亚人"
meet Samaritan.
他们不在这儿
They're not here.
那他们在哪儿
Then where are they?
我无法表达  这一刻我等了多久
I can't tell you how long I've waited for this moment.
我们大家等了多久
How long we've all been waiting.
现在就要将真相
Now is the time to expose the truth
公布于众
to our fellow citizens...
真相已经被隐藏太久
the truth that has been lurking beneath the shadows for so long...
以至于国已非国
that their country is no longer theirs...
自由已被剥夺
That their freedoms have been stripped away...
一台摄像机  一部手机  一兆字节  一点一滴
one camera, one cell phone, one megabyte at a time.
现在该拉开帷幕了
Now's the time to pull back the curtain.
欢迎来到你们的审判  女士们先生们
Welcome to your trial, ladies and gentlemen.
欢迎来到
And welcome to the trial...
对美国政府的审判
of the United States government.
现在开庭
Court is now in session.